<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Gautham Krishnan</title>
    <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Gautham Krishnan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Winning My First Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/winning-my-first-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/winning-my-first-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since the Hackathon and I am finding the motivation to write about it now. I am not sure why it took me so long to write. Probably because I&amp;rsquo;m lazy and the current semester break has left me with some extra time in which I find myself doing the random small things that I have been putting off for a long time.
Anyway, coming to the Hackathon, it was Hackverse 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Maths of Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/intro-to-maths-of-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/intro-to-maths-of-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning and AI have gained a lot of popularity because of the recent advancements in the field showing their capabilities for tasks like image detection, chat completion, image generation etc. At the base of all these models is Artifical Neural Networks(ANN). This article provides a basic understanding of maths and theoretical working of these networks.
Most of the maths present in this article comes under Linear Algebra and Calculus. Anyone who has done an undergrad course or two on these topics will be familiar with the concepts explained in the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U-Net Water Body Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/u-net-water-body-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/u-net-water-body-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>A project using the U-NET model for segmenting water bodies from satellite images. The model is deployed to Huggingface spaces using Gradio. This is one of my first D projects and I learned a lot doing this project.
Anyway its not a big deal, I just uploaded this project as a blog to test the working of this Hugo theme and I routinely modify it just to get the GitHub activity graph green.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
