<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gautham Krishnan</title>
    <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gautham Krishnan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gauthamk02.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Maths of Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/intro-to-maths-of-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/intro-to-maths-of-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning and AI have gained a lot of popularity because of the recent advancements in the field showing their capabilities for tasks like image detection, chat completion, image generation etc. At the base of all these models is Artifical Neural Networks(ANN). This article provides a basic understanding of maths and theoretical working of these networks.
Most of the maths present in this article comes under Linear Algebra and Calculus. Anyone who has done an undergrad course or two on these topics will be familiar with the concepts explained in the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello there, I see that you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the my website and is interested in knowing more &amp;ldquo;About Me&amp;rdquo;. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m from Kerala, India and am currently an undergrad student studying Computer Science in Amrita University. I spend time with neural networks and PyTorch when working and linear algebra when studying. If im not doing these two, you&amp;rsquo;ll find me at my room bending over any wierd fantasy/fiction book or at the beach looking at stray dogs (from a distance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U-Net Water Body Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/projects/unet-water-body-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/projects/unet-water-body-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>A project using the U-NET model for segmenting water bodies from satellite images. The model is deployed to Huggingface spaces using Gradio. This is one of my first D projects and I learned a lot doing this project.
Anyway its not a big deal, I just uploaded this project as a blog to test the working of this Hugo theme and I routinely modify it just to get the GitHub activity graph green.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
