<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gautham Krishnan</title>
    <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gautham Krishnan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gauthamk02.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A collection of links to the interesting things I find on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;blogs&#34;&gt;Blogs &lt;a href=&#34;#blogs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mit.edu/people/dpolicar/writing/prose/text/thinkingMeat.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re Made out of Meat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paulgraham.com/cities.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cities and Ambition - Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guzey.com/personal/what-should-you-do-with-your-life/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What Should You Do with Your Life? Directions and Advice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mit.edu/people/dpolicar/writing/prose/text/godTaoist.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Is God a Taoist?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kidger.site/thoughts/just-know-stuff/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Just know stuff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- &#xA;## Tweets&#xA;&#xA;1. [# on shortification of &#34;learning&#34; - Andrej Karpathy](https://x.com/karpathy/status/1756380066580455557)&#xA;2. [Go for a run](https://x.com/amor_fatti/status/1843830386746634591) --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bookshelf</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A collection of books that I&amp;rsquo;ve read and found interesting in no particular order along with a short summary and my thoughts on it. I will keep adding to the list as I read more books.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guns, Germs and Steel - Jared Diamond (Currently Reading):&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt; Explores the reasons for domination of few cultures over others including resource availability, social organization and technological advancements. More detailed and descriptive than Sapiens. Will add more details once I finish reading it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winning My First Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/winning-my-first-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/winning-my-first-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since the Hackathon and I am finding the motivation to write about it now. I am not sure why it took me so long to write. Probably because I&amp;rsquo;m lazy and the current semester break has left me with some extra time in which I find myself doing the random small things that I have been putting off for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, coming to the Hackathon, it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackverse.nitk.ac.in/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hackverse 4.0&lt;/a&gt; conducted by NITK-Surathkal and Devfolio. As with most of the hackathons that I participated in, it began with RV(Rajagopalan) sending the link to the hackathon and asking if we should participate in it. This was at the beginning of our 4th Semester when we completed our GSoC proposal submission when we all were pretty free and were looking for something to do. So the next evening in the amFOSS lab, we asked everyone if they were interested in participating and started forming teams. Unlike the usual team size of up to 4 members for hackathons, Hackverse only allowed a team size of up to 3. Initially, 9 of us were interested in participating and formed 4 teams in which I, Aashray and Abhinav were together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Maths of Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/intro-to-maths-of-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/intro-to-maths-of-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning and AI have gained a lot of popularity because of the recent advancements in the field showing their capabilities for tasks like image detection, chat completion, image generation etc. At the base of all these models is Artifical Neural Networks(ANN). This article provides a basic understanding of maths and theoretical working of these networks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the maths present in this article comes under Linear Algebra and Calculus. Anyone who has done an undergrad course or two on these topics will be familiar with the concepts explained in the article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hello&#34;&gt;Hello! &lt;a href=&#34;#hello&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a short introduction thats meant to give a general info about me to the people that stumble on this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Natively from Kerala, India, I&amp;rsquo;m currently a final year undergrad student studying Computer Science in Amrita University, Amritapuri — a beautiful coastal town where serene beaches, lush greenery and activities in the nearby ashram provide an inspiring backdrop for my life here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spend time with neural networks and PyTorch when working and linear algebra when studying. This has allowed me to work on many interesting research and open-source projects in the field of AI. Currently I am working on a Medical-AI Research project and have also contributed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://deepchem.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DeepChem&lt;/a&gt; as part of Google Summer of Code 2024.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U-Net Water Body Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/u-net-water-body-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gauthamk02.github.io/posts/u-net-water-body-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A project using the U-NET model for segmenting water bodies from satellite images. The model is deployed to Huggingface spaces using Gradio. This is one&#xA;of my first D projects and I learned a lot doing this project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway its not a big deal, I just uploaded this project as a blog to test the working of this Hugo theme and I routinely modify it just to get the GitHub&#xA;activity graph green. teehee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
